Chem Notes UP182
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Chem Notes
1992 -- 2007
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Department of Chemistry
UP182
0.25 Linear Feet
13 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes issues of Chem Notes. It is the newsletter of Tufts Chemistry department and includes department and alumni news.
Biographical / Historical
Professor Arthur Michael established the Department of Chemistry in 1882. In 1894, students were allowed for the first time to choose Chemistry as their academic major. Chemistry became one of twelve academic majors undergraduate students could choose as the focus of their studies.
The Department of Chemistry offers both its undergraduate and graduate students the resources and opportunities of a top-ranked research university while providing the individual attention, mentoring, and training of a smaller institution. Members of the Department provide guidance and advice to both undergraduates and graduates and work closely with them to ensure academic success.
Highly motivated undergraduates are encouraged to participate in a wide range of research projects under the leadership of faculty members. Research projects are varied in focus and deal with issues such as climate change, disease mitigation, and alternative energy.
The Department of Chemistry offers graduate programs at both the M.S. and the Ph.D. level in the following sub disciplines of Chemistry: organic, inorganic, physical, and analytical. The Department of Chemistry also offers joint graduate programs with the Tufts University Biotechnology Center. These joint graduate programs offer M.S. and Ph.D. degrees in Chemistry/Biotechnology for those students who are interested in applying their chemical training to emerging areas of biotechnology.
- Chem Notes, 1992 -- 2007; UP182.001; 0.25 Linear Feet; 13 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  Chem Notes is the newsletter of Tufts Chemistry department and includes department and alumni news.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Chem Notes, Spring, 1992; UP182.001.001.00001; Department of Chemistry
  - Chem Notes, Fall, 1993; UP182.001.001.00002; Department of Chemistry (Box 1)
  - Chem Notes, Spring, 1995; UP182.001.001.00003; Department of Chemistry (Box 1)
  - Chem Notes, Spring, 1996; UP182.001.001.00004; Department of Chemistry (Box 1)
  - Chem Notes, Spring-Summer, 1997; UP182.001.001.00005; Department of Chemistry (Box 1)
  - Chem Notes, Spring, 1998; UP182.001.001.00006; Department of Chemistry (Box 1)
  - Chem Notes, Spring, 1999; UP182.001.001.00007; Department of Chemistry
  - Chem Notes, Fall, 2000; UP182.001.001.00008; Department of Chemistry
  - Chem Notes, Winter, 2002; UP182.001.001.00009; Department of Chemistry (Box 1)
  - Chem Notes, Winter, 2003; UP182.001.001.00010; Department of Chemistry
  - Chem Notes, Winter, 2005; UP182.001.001.00011; Department of Chemistry
  - Chem Notes, Winter, 2006; UP182.001.001.00012; Department of Chemistry
  - Chem Notes, Spring, 2007; UP182.001.001.00013; Department of Chemistry (Box 1)